[
    {
        "question": "1. Compare Cloud and On-premise Computing.",
        "answer": "Criteria Cloud On-premise\nInitial cost Low High\nMaintenance and support Hassle-free Needs attention\nUpgrade Automatic Manual\nScalability Excellent Good\nPay as you go Yes No",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is a Cloud?",
        "answer": "A cloud is a collaboration of networks, hardware, services, storage, and interfaces that help in delivering computing as a service. It has three users:\nEnd users\nBusiness management users\n Cloud service providers\nLearn more about AWS from this insightful What is AWS Blog!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "It is an advanced-stage technology implemented so that the cloud provides its services globally as per the user requirements. It provides a method to access several servers worldwide.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are some of the key features of Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "Reliable\nScalable\nAgile\nLocation Independent\nMulti-tenant",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the benefits of Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "The main benefits of Cloud Computing are:\n Data backup and storage of data\n Powerful server capabilities\n Incremented productivity\n Cost-effective and time-saving\nGet started on your cloud computing project today and take advantage of the scalability, flexibility, and cost-effectiveness of the cloud!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Mention the layers of PaaS architecture.",
        "answer": "Cloud Controller\nAutomatically creates virtual machines and controllers\n Deploys applications\nConnects to services\nAutomatically scales up and down\nStorage Services\nObject\nNoSQL\nRelational\nBlock storage\nApplications Stored in Storage Services\nSimple-to-scale applications\nEasier recovery from failure",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are the cloud service models?",
        "answer": "Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)\nPlatform as a Service (PaaS)\nSoftware as a Service (SaaS)",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Write about Function as a Service.",
        "answer": "FaaS provides users with a fully functional platform where they can create, manage and run their applications without having to worry about maintaining the infrastructure.\nDo you want to become an AWS expert? Learn about the technology from Intellipaat’s AWS Certified Solutions Architect Course.\n\nGet 100% Hike!\nMaster Most in Demand Skills Now !\nBy providing your contact details, you agree to our Terms of Use & Privacy Policy",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What are the components of Windows Azure?",
        "answer": "Windows Azure Platform Services\nCloud\nSQL Azure\nApp Fabric: Allows fabric cloud",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What are the main constituents of the cloud ecosystem?",
        "answer": "Cloud service providers\nCloud consumers\nDirect consumers",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Who are the cloud consumers in a cloud ecosystem?",
        "answer": "People and teams who use different types of cloud services, within your organization.\nWant to master the core concepts of Azure? Check out our Microsoft Azure Training Course and become a Certified Administrator!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Who are the direct consumers in a cloud ecosystem?",
        "answer": "The individuals who utilize the service provided by your company, build within a cloud environment.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Who are the Cloud service providers in a cloud ecosystem?",
        "answer": "Cloud service providers are the companies that sell their cloud services to others. Sometimes these companies also provide cloud services internally to their partners, employees, etc.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What are the differences occurred in distributed operations?",
        "answer": "FC: Master–Slave operations\nNova: Parallel process and its shared database",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Which agent is equivalent of Nova Compute?",
        "answer": "Azure Agent\nBe a master of AWS by enrolling in Intellipaat’s AWS Training in Bangalore.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Mention the reliability and availability of Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "Use of Fault Domains:\nTwo virtual machines are in a single fault domain if a single piece of hardware can bring down both virtual machines.\nAzure automatically distributes instances of a role across fault domains.\n\nUse of Upgrade Domains:\nWhen a new version of the software is rolled out, then only one up-gradation of the domain is done at a time.\nIt ensures that any instance of the service is always available.\nThere is an availability of the applications in multiple instances.\n\nStorage and Network Availability:\nCopies of data are stored in different domains.\nit is a mechanism to guard against DoS and DDoS attacks.\nLook into the Cloud Computing Tutorial by Intellipaat.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. Explain the Cloud Computing Architecture.",
        "answer": "Cloud Computing Architecture brings together two components of cloud computing – the front-end and the back-end. It is important to bring the correct services together for the benefit of both internal and external people. If need be, cloud management should be able to quickly make the required changes.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What are the Cloud Storage Levels?",
        "answer": "Files\nBlocks\nDatasets\nObjects",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What are the differences between the three main Cloud service models: IaaS, PaaS, and SaaS?",
        "answer": "The differences between the three main Cloud service models are defined further:\nIaaS: IaaS stands for Infrastructure as a Service that offers networking resources, services and storage on-demand. Example: AWS\nPaaS: PaaS stands for Platform as a service, which allows users to develop, run, and manage applications offered by the third party. Example: Salesforce Lightning, AWS lambda etc.\nSaaS: SaaS stands for Software as a service also known as on-premise software, which delivers applications remotely over the internet. Example: Salesforce\nJoin our comprehensive training program with AWS Course in Hyderabad and become an AWS-certified professional.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. List some of the major benefits of using Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "Some of the major benefits of using Cloud Computing are as follows:\ni) Easy accessibility\nii) Centralized data security\niii) Cost Saving\niv) Automatic Software Updates\nv) Mobility",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Explain the concept of a Virtual Machine (VM) and its role in Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "A Virtual Machine in Cloud Computing can be understood as a virtual computer that runs on the top of a physical computer. It can store data, connect to networks, and can also do other computing functions.\nGo through the Cloud Computing Course Syllabus to learn about the curriculum in detail.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. Give examples of real-world applications of Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "Below are some examples of real-world applications of Cloud Computing:\nOnline Streaming Services\nE-commerce Businesses\nSocial Media Platforms\nEducational Platforms",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. What are some popular Cloud storage solutions?",
        "answer": "Below are some of the most prominent Cloud storage solutions:\nGoogle Drive\nMicrosoft OneDrive\nDropbox\nAmazon Drive\niCloud Drive\nIf you are interested in knowing about the AWS developer roadmap check out the How to Become an AWS Developer blog.\n\nIntermediate Cloud Computing Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. What are the serverless components in cloud computing with their advantages and disadvantages?",
        "answer": "These components allow you to create apps without the stress of managing the infrastructure.\nAdvantages Disadvantages\nCost-effective Can cause late responses\nIncreases productivity Not ideal for high-computing operations\nScalable More vulnerable when it comes to security\nNo server management Debugging is challenging\nTo know more pros and cons of cloud computing check our blog on the Advantages and disadvantages of cloud computing now!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. Give the best example of the open-source Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "OpenStack",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. What are microservices and their importance in the cloud?",
        "answer": "Microservices help create apps that consist of codes that are independent of one another and the platform they were developed on.  Microservices are important in the cloud because of the following reasons:\nEach of them is built for a particular purpose. This makes app development simpler.\nThey make changes easier and quicker. \nTheir scalability makes it easier to adapt the service as needed.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. What is an AMI? How do we implement it?",
        "answer": "AMI is Amazon Machine Image, which basically is a copy of your root file system. It feeds the information required to launch an instance.\nWe implement AMI by specifying an AMI whenever we want to launch an instance. Multiple instances can be launched from a single AMI with the same configuration.\nIn the case of launching instances with different configurations, we would need to launch different AMIs.\n\nAMI includes one or more snapshots of your EBS volumes, in the case of instance-store-backed AMIs, along with a template for the root volume of your instance (like an operating system, an application server, and applications).\nIt launches the permissions that decide which AWS accounts can use the AMI for launching instances. It also needs a block device mapping for specifying the volumes in order to attach them to the instances whenever they are launched.\nGo through the AWS Training in Chennai to clearly understand AWS!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. Why Hybrid Clouds are so important?",
        "answer": "Cloud Bursting:\nAccess capacity and specialized software are available in the public cloud and not in the private cloud.\nExamples: Virtual Amazon and Dynamo\nLeveraging the best of both public and private is the Hybrid Clouds.\nvCloud:\nIt is a VMware cloud.\nIt is expensive.\nIt gives enterprise quality.\nOpenStack:\nIt has commodity servers and storage.\nIt is less reliable.\nWe can run web servers on OpenStack.\nthe database is built on vCloud.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. List the platforms that are used for large-scale Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "The platforms that are used for large-scale Cloud Computing are:\nApache Hadoop\nMapReduce",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. Mention the different types of models used for the deployment in Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "The different deployment models in Cloud Computing are:\nPrivate Cloud\nPublic Cloud\nCommunity Cloud\nHybrid Cloud\nBecome a master of AWS by enrolling in this online AWS Training in Pune.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. Explain security management in terms of Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "Identity management access provides the authorization of application services.\nAccess control permission is given to users to have complete controlling access of another user who is entering into the cloud environment.\nAuthentication and Authorization permits only authorized and authenticated users to have access to the data and applications.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. Which are the layers of Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "The different layers used by cloud architecture are as follows:\nCLC or Cloud Controller\nWalrus\nCluster Controller\nStorage Controller (SC)\nNode Controller (NC)",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. Explain the full form and the usage of 'Eucalyptus' in Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "The full form of ‘Eucalyptus’ is ‘Elastic Utility Computing Architecture for Linking Your Programs to Useful Systems.\n\nEucalyptus is an open-source software infrastructure in Cloud Computing, which enables us to implement clusters on the Cloud Computing platform. It is mainly used to build public, hybrid, and private Clouds. It has the capability to convert one’s own data center into a private Cloud; it provides its functionalities to various other organizations.\nBe a master of AWS by enrolling in AWS Training in Mumbai.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. Mention the names of some large cloud providers and databases.",
        "answer": "Google Bigtable\nAmazon Simple Database\nCloud-based SQL (Sequential Query Language)",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "35. Explain the difference between cloud and traditional data centers.",
        "answer": "The traditional data center is expensive due to heating and hardware/software issues. Mostly, the expenditure is on the maintenance of the data centers.\nCloud is scaled up when there is an increase in demand, hence such expenditure issues are not faced in Cloud Computing.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "36. What is meant by Edge Computing?",
        "answer": "Edge computing is a part of the distributed computing structure. It brings companies closer to the sources of data. This benefits businesses by giving them better insights, good response time and better bandwidth.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "37. Describe the Cloud Computing architecture.",
        "answer": "Cloud Computing architecture is divided into two categories, and they are:\nFront End: Front End Cloud Computing architecture contains client-side interfaces and applications, which are required to access the Cloud Computing platforms and are used by the clients. Some examples are Web servers (Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer, etc.) and mobile devices, etc.\nBack End: Back End manages all the resources that are required to provide Cloud Computing services and is used by the service providers. It includes data storage, virtual machines, servers, traffic control mechanisms, etc.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "38. List out the different layers that define Cloud architecture.",
        "answer": "The different layers used by Cloud architecture are:\nCLC (Cloud Controller)\nWalrus\nCluster Controller\nSC (Storage Controller)\nNC (Node Controller)\nLearn more about AWS in a step-by-step guide through this AWS Tutorial.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "39. What are system integrators in Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "System integrators in Cloud Computing provide the strategy for the complicated process, which is used to design a Cloud platform.\nSince integrators have all the knowledge about data center creation, it allows them to create more accurate hybrid and private Cloud networks.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "40. Explain the use of “EUCALYPTUS” in Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "EUCALYPTUS is an open-source software infrastructure in Cloud Computing, which stands for Elastic Utility Computing Architecture, used to implement clusters in Cloud Computing platforms.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "41. What is Amazon SQS?",
        "answer": "Amazon SQS acts as a communicator, which is used to communicate between different components of Amazon.\nEnroll today to level up your AWS Cloud skills with this AWS training in Kolkata.\n\nAdvanced Cloud Computing Interview Questions for Experienced",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "42. What are the uses of APIs in cloud services?",
        "answer": "APIs (Application Programming Interfaces) are used to eliminate the necessity to write complete programs.\nHere, instructions are provided to make communication between one or more applications.\nCreation of applications is made easy and accessible for the link of cloud services with other systems.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. Mention different data center deployments of Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "Cloud Computing consists of different data centers as follows:\nContainerized data centers: Containerized data centers are packages that contain a consistent set of servers, network components, and storage delivered to large warehouse kind of facilities. Here, each deployment is relatively unique.\nLow-density data centers: Containerized data centers promote heavy density which in turn causes much heat and significant engineering troubles. Low-density data centers are the solution to this problem. Here, the equipment is established far apart so that it cools down the generated heat.\nEnroll now to take your cloud computing skills to the next level through our Cloud Computing Courses.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. List down the three basic functioning clouds in Cloud Computing.",
        "answer": "Professional cloud\nPersonal cloud\nPerformance cloud",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. What are the characteristics of cloud architecture that differ from traditional cloud architecture?",
        "answer": "The characteristics are:\n In cloud, the hardware requirement is fulfilled as per the demand created for cloud architecture.\nCloud architecture is capable of scaling up resources when there is a demand.\nCloud architecture is capable of managing and handling dynamic workloads without any point of failure.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "46. What are the building blocks of cloud architecture?",
        "answer": "Reference architecture\nTechnical architecture\nDeployment operation architecture",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "47. Explain AWS.",
        "answer": "AWS stands for Amazon Web Services which is a collection of remote computing services also known as Cloud Computing. This technology is also known as IaaS or Infrastructure as a Service.\nBe a master of AWS by enrolling in AWS Training in Delhi.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "48. Mention the key components of AWS.",
        "answer": "The key components of AWS are as follows:\nAWS Route 53: AWS Route 53 is a DNS (Domain Name Server) web-based service platform.\nSimple E-mail Service (AWS SES): Sending of e-mail is done by using a RESTFUL API call or via regular SMTP (Simple Mail Transfer Protocol).\nIdentity and Access Management (AWS IAM): Improvised security and identity management are provided for an AWS account.\nSimple Storage Device (S3): It is a huge storage medium, widely used for AWS services.\nElastic Compute Cloud (EC2): It allows on-demand computing resources for hosting applications and is essentially useful for unpredictable workloads.\nElastic Block Stores (EBS): They are storage volumes attached to EC2 and allow the data lifespan of a single EC2.\nCloudWatch: Amazon CloudWatch is used to monitor AWS resources, and it allows administrators to view and collect the keys required. Access is provided so that one can set a notification alarm in the case of trouble.\nGo through the Challenges of Cloud Computing Blog to know about the challenges you can face while working.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "49. Explain how you can vertically scale an Amazon instance.",
        "answer": "This is one of the essential features of AWS and cloud virtualization. We spinup a newly developed large instance where we pause that instance and detach the root EBS volume from the server and discard. Later, we stop our live instance and detach its root volume connected. here, we note down the unique device ID and attach the same root volume to the new server, and we restart it again. This results in a vertically scaled Amazon instance.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "50. Explain the security usage in the Amazon Web Services model.",
        "answer": "AWS supports security groups.\nAccess is provided to create a security group for a jump box with SSH access only for port 22 open. Later, a webserver group and a database group are created. The webserver group provides 80 and 443 from around the world, but only port 22 will be vital among the jump box group. The database group allows port 3306 from the webserver group and port 22 from the jump box group. The addition of any machines to the webserver group can store in the database. No one can directly SSH to any of our boxes.\n\nWatch this Cloud Computing Full Course video:",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "51. What are reasons that make Amazon so big?",
        "answer": "In Amazon, the backup storage of EBS volumes is maintained by inserting the snapshot facility via an API call or via a GUI interface like Elasticfox.\nPerformance is improved by using Linux software RAID and striping across four volumes.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "52. How does Resource Replication take place in Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "Resource Replication creates duplicates of the same resource. Replication is employed when a resource is needed more and more. The resource is virtualized to replicate cloud-based resources.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "53. What is Containers as a Service (CaaS)?",
        "answer": "CaaS is a system that allows developers to run, scale, manage, upload, and organize containers by using virtualization.\nA container is a software pack. It allows teams to scale their apps to highly available cloud infrastructures. \nHope that you will find these interview questions for the role of Cloud Engineer useful. Do let us know in the comments section below!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "54. Can you explain how Cloud Computing differs from traditional data center operations?",
        "answer": "The process of storing, processing and managing the data online on servers is known as Cloud Computing, whereas storing, processing and managing these records or data through physical servers is traditional data centers.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "55. What is Cloud migration and what are its benefits?",
        "answer": "The process of transferring data, applications and some other IT resources from an organization’s on-premises to Cloud based infrastructure is known as Cloud migration. Below are some of the mentioned advantages of Cloud migration:\nCost Optimization\nScalability and Elasticity\nPerformance and Reliability\nSpeed",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "56. What are containerized data centres?",
        "answer": "Containerized data centres can be classified as those data centers that allow a high level of customization with servers and other resources.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "57. What are some issues with Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "Below are some of the issues with Cloud Computing:\nSecurity issues\nLegal and Compliance issues\nPerformance issue\nQuality of service related issues\nData Management issues",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "58. What do you mean by rate limiting?",
        "answer": "Rate limiting is a way to limit the network traffic, which runs within the app rather than the server and tracks the IP addresses and the time between each request. Other than limiting network traffic, it can also eliminate certain suspicious and malicious activities.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "59. How does Cloud-native foundation define Cloud-native applications?",
        "answer": "The Cloud-native applications are elaborated below:\nContainer packaged: Standard container packaging formats should be used to package applications.\nDynamically managed: Should follow the standard format to discover, deploy, and scale applications.\nMicroservices oriented: decompose applications into modular, independent services.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "60. What is encapsulation?",
        "answer": "Encapsulation in Cloud refers to the techniques of packaging the software code along with all of its dependencies, so that it can consistently run on both Cloud and also on-premises.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "61. How does resource replication take place in Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "Creating multiple instances of the same IT resources in order to enhance the availability and performance of a resource is known as resource replication. In the Cloud, virtualization technology helps in implementing this.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "62. What is a Cloud usage monitor?",
        "answer": "Cloud usage monitor is an autonomous, lightweight software program that gathers and processes usage data of IT resources. These monitors can exist in various formats like resource agent, polling agent, and monitoring agent.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What is a Cloud Technology?",
        "answer": "A cloud is a combination of services, networks, hardware, storage, and interfaces that helps in delivering computing as a service. It broadly has three users. These are the end-user, business management user, and cloud service, provider. The end-user is the one who uses the services provided by the cloud. The responsibility of the data and the services provided by the cloud is taken by the business management user in the cloud. The one who takes care of or is responsible for the maintenance of the IT assets of the cloud is the cloud service provider. The cloud acts as a common center for its users to fulfill their computing needs.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What are the Cloud Storage Levels?",
        "answer": "Cloud storage device mechanisms provide common levels of data storage, such as: Files – These are collections of data that are grouped into files that are located in folders.\nBlocks – A block is the smallest unit of data that is individually accessible. It is the lowest level of storage and the closest to the hardware.\nDatasets – Data sets organized into a table-based, delimited, or record format.\nObjects – Data and the associated metadata with it are organized as web-based resources. Files – These are collections of data that are grouped into files that are located in folders. Files Blocks – A block is the smallest unit of data that is individually accessible. It is the lowest level of storage and the closest to the hardware. Blocks Datasets – Data sets organized into a table-based, delimited, or record format. Datasets Objects – Data and the associated metadata with it are organized as web-based resources. Objects Each of the above data storage levels is associated with a certain type of technical interface. This interface corresponds to a particular type of cloud storage device and the cloud storage service used to expose its API.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Describe the Cloud Computing Architecture.",
        "answer": "The cloud computing architecture is all the components of a cloud model that fit together from an architectural perspective. The figure below depicts how the various cloud services are related to support the needs of businesses. On the left side, the cloud service consumer represents the types of uses of cloud services. No matter what the requirements of the particular constituent are, it is important to bring the right type of services together that can support both internal and external users. Management of the consumers should be able to make services readily available to support the changing business needs. The applications, middleware, infrastructure, and services that are built based on on-premises computing models are within this category. In addition to this, the model depicts the role of a cloud auditor. This organization provides an oversight either by an internal or external group which makes sure that the consumer group meets its obligations. The NIST Cloud Reference Model  The NIST Cloud Reference Model",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Who are the Cloud service providers in a cloud ecosystem?",
        "answer": "Cloud service providers are the commercial vendors or companies that create their own capabilities. The commercial vendors sell their services to cloud consumers. In contrast to this, a company might decide to become an internal cloud service provider to its own partners, employees, and customers, either as an internal service or as a profit center. Cloud service providers also create applications or services for such environments.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Who are the Direct customers in a cloud ecosystem?",
        "answer": "Users who often take advantage of services that your business has created within a cloud environment. The end-users of your service have no idea that you’re using a public or private cloud. As long as the users are concerned, they’re interacting directly with the services and value.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Who are the Cloud Consumers in a cloud ecosystem?",
        "answer": "The individuals and groups within your business unit that use different types of cloud services to get a task accomplished. A cloud consumer could be a developer using compute services from a public cloud.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are the main constituents that are part of the cloud ecosystem?",
        "answer": "The parts of the cloud ecosystem that determine how you view the cloud architecture are: Cloud consumers\nDirect customers\nCloud service providers Cloud consumers Direct customers Cloud service providers",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What are the different versions of the cloud?",
        "answer": "There are two primary deployment models of the cloud: Public and Private. Public Private Public  Cloud: The set of hardware, networking, storage, services, applications, and interfaces owned and operated by a third party for use by other companies or individuals is the public cloud. These commercial providers create a highly scalable data center that hides the details of the underlying infrastructure from the consumer. Public clouds are viable because they offer many options for computing, storage, and a rich set of other services.\nPrivate Cloud: The set of hardware, networking, storage, services, applications, and interfaces owned and operated by an organization for the use of its employees, partners, or customers is the private cloud. This can be created and managed by a third party for the exclusive use of one enterprise. The private cloud is a highly controlled environment not open for public consumption. Thus, it sits behind a firewall.\nHybrid Cloud: Most companies use a combination of private computing resources and public services, called the hybrid cloud environment. \nMulti-Cloud: Some companies, in addition, also use a variety of public cloud services to support the different developer and business units – called a multi-cloud environment. Public  Cloud: The set of hardware, networking, storage, services, applications, and interfaces owned and operated by a third party for use by other companies or individuals is the public cloud. These commercial providers create a highly scalable data center that hides the details of the underlying infrastructure from the consumer. Public clouds are viable because they offer many options for computing, storage, and a rich set of other services. Public  Cloud: Private Cloud: The set of hardware, networking, storage, services, applications, and interfaces owned and operated by an organization for the use of its employees, partners, or customers is the private cloud. This can be created and managed by a third party for the exclusive use of one enterprise. The private cloud is a highly controlled environment not open for public consumption. Thus, it sits behind a firewall. Private Cloud: Hybrid Cloud: Most companies use a combination of private computing resources and public services, called the hybrid cloud environment. Hybrid Cloud: Multi-Cloud: Some companies, in addition, also use a variety of public cloud services to support the different developer and business units – called a multi-cloud environment. Multi-Cloud:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What do you mean by cloud delivery models?",
        "answer": "Cloud delivery models are models that represent the computing environments. These are as follows: Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS): Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) is the delivery of services, including an operating system, storage, networking, and various utility software elements, on a request basis. \nPlatform as a Service (PaaS): Platform as a Service (PaaS) is a mechanism for combining Infrastructure as a Service with an abstracted set of middleware services, software development, and deployment tools. These allow the organization to have a consistent way to create and deploy applications on a cloud or on-premises environment.\nSoftware as a Service (SaaS): Software as a Service (SaaS) is a business application created and hosted by a provider in a multi-tenant model. \nFunction as a Service (FaaS): Function as a Service (FaaS) gives a platform for customers to build, manage and run app functionalities without the difficulty of maintaining infrastructure. One can thus achieve a \"serverless\" architecture. Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS): Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) is the delivery of services, including an operating system, storage, networking, and various utility software elements, on a request basis. Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS): Platform as a Service (PaaS): Platform as a Service (PaaS) is a mechanism for combining Infrastructure as a Service with an abstracted set of middleware services, software development, and deployment tools. These allow the organization to have a consistent way to create and deploy applications on a cloud or on-premises environment. Platform as a Service (PaaS): Software as a Service (SaaS): Software as a Service (SaaS) is a business application created and hosted by a provider in a multi-tenant model. Software as a Service (SaaS): Function as a Service (FaaS): Function as a Service (FaaS) gives a platform for customers to build, manage and run app functionalities without the difficulty of maintaining infrastructure. One can thus achieve a \"serverless\" architecture. Function as a Service (FaaS):  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What are some of the key features of Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "The following are some of the key features of cloud computing: Agility: Helps in quick and inexpensive re-provisioning of resources.\nLocation Independence: This means that the resources can be accessed from everywhere.\nMulti-Tenancy: The resources are shared amongst a large group of users.\nReliability: Resources and computation can be dependable for accessibility.\nScalability: Dynamic provisioning of data helps in scaling. Agility: Helps in quick and inexpensive re-provisioning of resources. Agility: Location Independence: This means that the resources can be accessed from everywhere. Location Independence: Multi-Tenancy: The resources are shared amongst a large group of users. Multi-Tenancy: Reliability: Resources and computation can be dependable for accessibility. Reliability: Scalability: Dynamic provisioning of data helps in scaling. Scalability:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What is the cloud usage monitor?",
        "answer": "The cloud usage monitor mechanism is an autonomous and lightweight software program that is responsible for collecting and processing the IT resource usage data. Cloud usage monitors can exist in different formats depending on what type of usage metrics these are designed to collect and how the usage data needs to be collected. The following points describe 3 common agent-based implementation formats. Monitoring Agent\nResource Agent\nPolling Agent Monitoring Agent Resource Agent Polling Agent",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. How does Resource Replication take place in Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "Resource Replication is the creation of multiple instances of the same IT resource. It is typically performed when an IT resource’s availability and performance are needed to be enhanced. The virtualization technology is adopted to implement the resource replication mechanism in order to replicate the cloud-based IT resources.   Conclusion: Cloud computing is completely based on the Internet. It is the next stage in the evolution of the Internet. Cloud computing uses the cloud that provides the way to deliver the services whenever and wherever the user needs them. Enterprises use cloud computing to provide solutions to the needs of their customers, partners, and providers. Cloud computing includes partners, vendors, and business leaders as the three major contributors. The vendors provide applications and their related technology, infrastructure, hardware, and integration. The partners offer cloud services and provide support services to the customers. The business leaders evaluate the cloud service provided by the partners. \nCloud computing enables enterprises to treat their resources as a pool and not as independent resources.  References: References: Cloud Computing: Concepts, Technology & Architecture by Zaigham Mahmood; Ricardo Puttini; Thomas Erl, Published by Pearson, 2013\nCloud Computing by Lizhe Wang; Rajiv Ranjan; Jinjun Chen; Boualem Benatallah, Published by CRC Press, 2017 Cloud Computing: Concepts, Technology & Architecture by Zaigham Mahmood; Ricardo Puttini; Thomas Erl, Published by Pearson, 2013 Cloud Computing by Lizhe Wang; Rajiv Ranjan; Jinjun Chen; Boualem Benatallah, Published by CRC Press, 2017 Recommended Resources: Recommended Resources: Data Science Interview\nAWS Interview\nAzure Interview\nMachine Learning Interview\nCharacteristics of Cloud Computing\nCloud Computing Projects\nApplications of Cloud Computing\nCloud Engineer Salary\nWhat is a Cloud Engineer? Data Science Interview Data Science Interview AWS Interview AWS Interview Azure Interview Azure Interview Machine Learning Interview Machine Learning Interview Characteristics of Cloud Computing Characteristics of Cloud Computing Cloud Computing Projects Cloud Computing Projects Applications of Cloud Computing Applications of Cloud Computing Cloud Engineer Salary Cloud Engineer Salary What is a Cloud Engineer? What is a Cloud Engineer?",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What are some issues with Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "Following are some of the issues of cloud computing: Security Issues: As it would be in any other computing paradigms, security is as much of a concern as Cloud computing. Cloud Computing is vaguely defined as the outsourcing of services, which in turn causes users to lose significant control over their data. With the public Cloud, there is also a risk of seizure associated.\nLegal and Compliance Issues: Sometimes, clouds are bounded by geographical boundaries. The provision of different services is not location-dependent. Because of this flexibility Clouds face Legal & Compliance issues. Though these issues affect the end-users, they are related mainly to the vendors.\nPerformance and Quality of Service (QoS) Related Issues: Paradigm performance is of utmost importance for any computing. The Quality of Service (QoS) varies as the user requirements may vary. One of the critical Quality of Service-related issues is the optimized way in which commercial success can be achieved using Cloud computing. If a provider is unable to deliver the promised QoS it may tarnish its reputation. One faces the issue of Memory and Licensing constraints which directly hamper the performance of a system, as Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) deals with the provision of software on virtualized resources,\nData Management Issues: An important use case of Cloud Computing is to put almost the entire data on the Cloud with minimum infrastructure requirements for the end-users. The main problems related to data management are scalability of data, storage of data, data migration from one cloud to another, and also different architectures for resource access. It is of utmost importance to manage these data effectively, as data in Cloud computing also includes highly confidential information. Security Issues: As it would be in any other computing paradigms, security is as much of a concern as Cloud computing. Cloud Computing is vaguely defined as the outsourcing of services, which in turn causes users to lose significant control over their data. With the public Cloud, there is also a risk of seizure associated. Security Issues Legal and Compliance Issues: Sometimes, clouds are bounded by geographical boundaries. The provision of different services is not location-dependent. Because of this flexibility Clouds face Legal & Compliance issues. Though these issues affect the end-users, they are related mainly to the vendors. Legal and Compliance Issues Performance and Quality of Service (QoS) Related Issues: Paradigm performance is of utmost importance for any computing. The Quality of Service (QoS) varies as the user requirements may vary. One of the critical Quality of Service-related issues is the optimized way in which commercial success can be achieved using Cloud computing. If a provider is unable to deliver the promised QoS it may tarnish its reputation. One faces the issue of Memory and Licensing constraints which directly hamper the performance of a system, as Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) deals with the provision of software on virtualized resources, Performance and Quality of Service (QoS) Related Issues Data Management Issues: An important use case of Cloud Computing is to put almost the entire data on the Cloud with minimum infrastructure requirements for the end-users. The main problems related to data management are scalability of data, storage of data, data migration from one cloud to another, and also different architectures for resource access. It is of utmost importance to manage these data effectively, as data in Cloud computing also includes highly confidential information. Data Management Issues",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are Low-Density Data Centers?",
        "answer": "Low-Density Data Centers are optimized to give high performance. The space constraint is being removed and there is an increased density in these data centers. One drawback it has is that with high density the heat issue also creeps in. These data centers are quite suitable to develop the cloud infrastructure.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are Containerized Data Centers?",
        "answer": "Containerized Data Centers are the traditional data centers that allow a high level of customization with servers, mainframes, and other resources. These require planning, cooling, networking, and power to access and work.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What are the different Datacenters deployed for Cloud Computing?",
        "answer": "Cloud computing is made up of various data centers put together in a grid form. It consists of the data centers like: Containerized Data Centers\nLow-Density Data Centers Containerized Data Centers Low-Density Data Centers",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What do you mean by encapsulation in cloud computing?",
        "answer": "A container is a packaged software code along with all of its dependencies so that it can run consistently across clouds and on-premises. This packaging up of code is often called encapsulation. Encapsulating code is important for developers as they don’t have to develop code based on each individual environment.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What do you mean by Rate Limiting?",
        "answer": "Rate Limiting is a way to limit the network traffic. Rate limiting runs within the app rather than the server. It typically tracks the IP addresses and the time between each request. It can eliminate certain suspicious and malicious activities. Bots that impact a website can also be stopped by Rate Limiting. This protects against API overuse which is important to prevent.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is an API Gateway?",
        "answer": "An API gateway allows multiple APIs to act together as a single gateway to provide a uniform experience to the user. In this, each API call is processed reliably. The API gateway manages the APIs centrally and provides enterprise-grade security. Common tasks of the API services can be handled by the API gateway. These tasks include services like statistics, rate limiting, and user authentication.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What is meant by Edge Computing?",
        "answer": "Edge and cloud are complementary. These are both parts of a broader concept called the distributed cloud. A majority of those pursuing edge computing strategies are now viewing edge as part of their overall cloud strategy. Edge computing, unlike cloud computing, is all about the physical location and issues related to latency. Cloud and edge combine the strengths of a centralized system, along with the advantages of distributed operations at the physical location where things and people connect. In IoT scenarios, the edge is very common. Cloud is different from the edge, in that it has never been about location. As opposed, it has always been about the independence of location. The popular scenarios are where you have cloud and edge together, and the cloud provider controls to run and defines the architecture for what is out at the edge.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. How does the Cloud Native Computing Foundation define cloud-native applications?",
        "answer": "The Cloud Native Computing Foundation gives a clear definition of cloud-native: Container packaged: This means a standard way to package applications that is resource-efficient. By using a standard container format, more applications can be densely packed.\nDynamically managed: This means a standard way to discover, deploy, and scale up and down containerized applications.\nMicroservices oriented: This means a method to decompose the application into modular, independent services that interact through well-defined service contracts. Container packaged: This means a standard way to package applications that is resource-efficient. By using a standard container format, more applications can be densely packed. Container packaged: Dynamically managed: This means a standard way to discover, deploy, and scale up and down containerized applications. Dynamically managed: Microservices oriented: This means a method to decompose the application into modular, independent services that interact through well-defined service contracts. Microservices oriented:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What are Cloud-Native Applications?",
        "answer": "‘Cloud native’ is a software framework designed with containers, microservices, dynamic orchestration, and also continuous delivery of software. Every part of the cloud-native application has within it its own container and is dynamically orchestrated with other containers to optimize the way the resources are utilized.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. How does the Polling Agent monitor cloud usage?",
        "answer": "A processing module that gathers cloud service usage data by polling IT resources is called a polling agent. The polling agent has also been used to timely monitor the IT resource status, like uptime and downtime.\nEach of these can be designed to forward collected usage data to a log database for post-processing and for reporting purposes. ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. How does the Resource Agent monitor the cloud usage?",
        "answer": "A processing module that is used to collect usage data by having event-driven interactions with the specialized resource software, is a resource agent. This agent is applied to check the usage metrics based on pre-defined, observable events at the resource software level, like initiating, suspending, resuming, and vertical scaling.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. How does the Monitoring Agent monitor the cloud usage?",
        "answer": "An intermediary and an event-driven program that exists as a service agent and resides along the existing communication paths is a monitoring agent.  It transparently monitors and analyzes dataflows. Commonly, the monitoring agent is used to measure the network traffic and also message metrics.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Why are microservices important for a true cloud environment?",
        "answer": "The reason why microservices are so important for a true cloud environment is because of these four key benefits: Each microservice is built to serve a specific and limited purpose, and hence application development is simplified. Small development teams can then focus on writing code for some of the narrowly defined and easily understood functions.\nCode changes will be smaller and less complex than with a complex integrated application, making it easier and faster to make changes, whether to fix a problem or to upgrade service with new requirements.\nScalability — Scalability makes it easier to deploy an additional instance of a service or change that service as needs evolve.\nMicroservices are fully tested and validated. When new applications leverage existing microservices, developers can assume the integrity of the new application without the need for continual testing. Each microservice is built to serve a specific and limited purpose, and hence application development is simplified. Small development teams can then focus on writing code for some of the narrowly defined and easily understood functions. Code changes will be smaller and less complex than with a complex integrated application, making it easier and faster to make changes, whether to fix a problem or to upgrade service with new requirements. Scalability — Scalability makes it easier to deploy an additional instance of a service or change that service as needs evolve. Microservices are fully tested and validated. When new applications leverage existing microservices, developers can assume the integrity of the new application without the need for continual testing.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What are Microservices?",
        "answer": "Microservices is a process of developing applications that consist of code that is independent of each other and of the underlying developing platform. Each microservice runs a unique process and communicates through well-defined and standardized APIs, once created. These services are defined in the form of a catalog so that developers can easily locate the right service and also understand the governance rules for usage. Microservices",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What are cloud-enabling technologies?",
        "answer": "There are several areas of technology that contribute to modern-day cloud-based platforms. These are known as cloud-enabling technologies. Some of the cloud-enabling technologies are: Broadband Networks and Internet Architecture\nData Center Technology\n(Modern) Virtualization Technology\nWeb Technology\nMultitenant Technology\nService Technology Broadband Networks and Internet Architecture Data Center Technology (Modern) Virtualization Technology Web Technology Multitenant Technology Service Technology",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What are the advantages and disadvantages of serverless computing?",
        "answer": "Serverless computing has the following advantages and disadvantages:\nAdvantages:  Advantages: It is cost-effective.\nThe operations on serverless computing are simplified.\nServerless computing helps boost productivity.\nIt offers scaling options.\nIt involves zero server management. It is cost-effective. The operations on serverless computing are simplified. Serverless computing helps boost productivity. It offers scaling options. It involves zero server management. Disadvantages: Disadvantages: Serverless code can cause response latency.\nIt is not ideal for high-computing operations because of resource limitations.\nFor serverless computing, the responsibility of security comes under the service company and not the consumer, which might be more vulnerable.\nDebugging serverless code is a bit more challenging. Serverless code can cause response latency. It is not ideal for high-computing operations because of resource limitations. For serverless computing, the responsibility of security comes under the service company and not the consumer, which might be more vulnerable. Debugging serverless code is a bit more challenging.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. What are serverless components in cloud computing?",
        "answer": "Serverless components in cloud computing allow the building of applications to take place without the complexity of managing the infrastructure. One can write code without having provision to a server. Serverless machines take care of virtual machines and container management. Multithreading, hardware allocating are also taken care of by the serverless components.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is cloud computing?",
        "answer": "Cloud computing is an internet based new age computer technology. It is the next stage technology that uses the clouds to provide the services whenever and wherever the user need it.It provides a method to access several servers world wide.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) What are the benefits of cloud computing?",
        "answer": "The main benefits of cloud computing are:\nADVERTISEMENT\nData backup and storage of data.\nPowerful server capabilities.\nIncremented productivity.\nVery cost effective and time saving.\nSoftware as Service known as SaaS.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) What is a cloud?",
        "answer": "A cloud is a combination of networks ,hardware, services, storage, and interfaces that helps in delivering computing as a service. It has three users :\nEnd users\nBusiness management users\ncloud service provider",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What are the different data types used in cloud computing?",
        "answer": "There are different data types in cloud computing like emails, contracts, images , blogs etc. As we know that data is increasing day by day so it is needed to new data types to store these new data. For an example, if you want to store video then you need a new data type.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) Which are the different layers that define cloud architecture?",
        "answer": "Following are the different layers that are used by cloud architecture:\nCLC or Cloud Controller\nWalrus\nCluster Controller\nSC or Storage Controller\nNC or Node Controller",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) Which platforms are used for large scale cloud computing?",
        "answer": "The following platforms are used for large scale cloud computing:\nApache Hadoop\nMapReduce",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "There are 3 layers in the hierarchy of cloud computing.\nInfrastructure as a service (IaaS):It provides cloud infrastructure in terms of hardware as like memory, processor, speed etc.\nPlatform as a service (PaaS):It provides cloud application platform for the developer.\nSoftware as a service (SaaS)::It provides the cloud applications to users directly without installing anything on the system. These applications remains on cloud.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What do you mean by software as a service?",
        "answer": "Software As a Service (SaaS) is an important layer of cloud computing. It provides cloud applications like Google is doing. It facilitate users to save their document on the cloud and create as well.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What is the platform as a service?",
        "answer": "It is also a layer in cloud architecture. This model is built on the infrastructure model and provide resources like computers, storage and network. It is responsible to provide complete virtualization of the infrastructure layer, make it look like a single server and invisible for outside world.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What is on-demand functionality? How is it provided in cloud computing?",
        "answer": "Cloud computing provides a on-demand access to the virtualized IT resources. It can be used by the subscriber. It uses shared pool to provide configurable resources. Shared pool contains networks, servers, storage, applications and services.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) What are the platforms used for large scale cloud computing?",
        "answer": "Apache Hadoop and MapReduce are the platforms use for large scale cloud computing.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What are the different models for deployment in cloud computing?",
        "answer": "These are the different deployment model in cloud computing:\nPrivate cloud\nPublic cloud\nHybrid cloud\nCommunity cloud",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) What is private cloud?",
        "answer": "Private clouds are used to keep the strategic operations and other reasons secure. It is a complete platform which is fully functional and can be owned, operated and restricted to only an organization or an industry. Now a day, most of the organizations have moved to private clouds due to security concerns. Virtual private cloud is being used that operate by a hosting company.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) What is public cloud?",
        "answer": "The public clouds are open to the people for use and deployment. For example: Google and Amazon etc. The public clouds focus on a few layers like cloud application, infrastructure providing and providing platform markets.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) What are Hybrid clouds?",
        "answer": "Hybrid clouds are the combination of public clouds and private clouds. It is preferred over both the clouds because it applies most robust approach to implement cloud architecture. It includes the functionalities and features of both the worlds. It allows organizations to create their own cloud and allow them to give the control over to someone else as well.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What is the difference between cloud computing and mobile computing?",
        "answer": "Mobile computing and cloud computing are slightly same in concept. Mobile computing uses the concept of cloud computing . Cloud computing provides users the data which they required while in mobile computing, applications run on the remote server and gives user the access for storage and manage.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) What is the difference between scalability and elasticity?",
        "answer": "Scalability is a characteristic of cloud computing which is used to handle the increasing workload by increasing in proportion amount of resource capacity. By the use of scalability, the architecture provides on demand resources if the requirement is being raised by the traffic. Whereas, Elasticity is a characteristic which provides the concept of commissioning and decommissioning of large amount of resource capacity dynamically. It is measured by the speed by which the resources are coming on demand and the usage of the resources.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What are the security benefits of cloud computing?",
        "answer": "Cloud computing authorizes the application service, so it is used in identity management.\nIt provides permissions to the users so that they can control the access of another user who is entering into the cloud environment.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) What is the usage of utility computing?",
        "answer": "Utility computing is a plug-in managed by an organization which decides what type of services has to be deployed from the cloud. It facilitates users to pay only for what they use.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What is \"EUCALYPTUS\" in cloud computing? Why is it used?",
        "answer": "It is an acronym stands for Elastic Utility Computing Architecture For Linking Your Program To Useful Systems. It is an open source software infrastructure in cloud computing and used to implement clusters in cloud computing platform. It creates public, private and hybrid cloud. It facilitate a user to create his own data center into a private cloud and use its functionalities to many other organizations.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "System integrator provides a strategy of a complicated process used to design a cloud platform. It creates more accurate hybrid and private cloud network because integrator have all the knowledge about the data center creation.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) What are the open source cloud computing platform databases?",
        "answer": "MongoDB, CouchDB, LucidDB are the example of open source cloud computing platform database.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) Give some example of large cloud provider and databases?",
        "answer": "Google bigtable\nAmazon simpleDB\nCloud based SQL",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What is the difference between cloud and traditional datacenters?",
        "answer": "The cost of the traditional datacenter is higher than cloud because in traditional databases, there is overheating problems and some software and hardware issue.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) What are the different in Software as a Service (SaaS)?",
        "answer": "Simple Multi-tenancy:In this mode, Every user has independent resources and are uniquely different from other users. This is an efficient mode.\nFine grain multi-tenancy:: In this mode, the resources can be shared by many users but the functionality remains the same.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) Why API's is used in cloud services?",
        "answer": "API's (Application Programming Interfaces) is used in cloud platform because:\nIt provide an alternative way that you don't need to write the fully fledged program.\nIt makes communication between one or more applications.\nIt creates applications and link the cloud services with other systems.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) What are the advantages of cloud services?",
        "answer": "Following are the main advantages of cloud services:\nCost saving: It helps in the utilization of investment in the corporate sector. So, it is cost saving.\nScalable and Robust: It helps in the developing scalable and robust applications. Previously, the scaling took months, but now, scaling takes less time.\nTime saving: It helps in saving time in terms of deployment and maintenance.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) What are the different datacenters in cloud computing?",
        "answer": "Containerized datacenter\nLow density datacenter",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) What do you mean by CaaS?",
        "answer": "CaaS is a terminology used in telecom industry as Communication As a Service. CaaS offers the enterprise user features such as desktop call control, unified messaging and desktop faxing.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) What do you mean by VPN? What does it contain?",
        "answer": "VPN stands for Virtual Private Network. VPN is a private cloud that manage the security of the data during the communication in the cloud environment. With VPN, you can make a public network as private network.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) What are the basic clouds in cloud computing?",
        "answer": "There are three basic clouds in cloud computing:\nProfessional cloud\nPersonal cloud\nPerformance cloud",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) What are the most essential things that must be followed before going for cloud computing platform?",
        "answer": "Compliance\nLoss of data\nData storage\nBusiness continuity\nUptime\nData integrity in cloud computing",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) Which services are provided by Window azure operating system?",
        "answer": "There are three core services provided by Window azure operating system:\nCompute\nStorage\nManagement",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "34) What is the usage of virtualization platform in implementing cloud?",
        "answer": "The main usage of virtualization platform in implementing cloud is:\nIt is used to manage the service level policies.\nCloud Operating System.\nVirtualization platforms help to keep the backend level and user level concepts different from each other.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) We source cloud computing platform databases?",
        "answer": "Following are the open source cloud computing platform databases:\nMongoDB\nCouchDB\nLucidDB",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) What are some large cloud providers and databases?",
        "answer": "Following are the mostly used large cloud providers and databases:\nGoogle bigtable\nAmazon simpleDB\nCloud based SQL",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    },
    {
        "question": "37) How would you secure data for transport in cloud?",
        "answer": "This is the most obvious question accurued in mind that if the cloud data is secure; To ensure that, check that there is no data leak with the encryption key implemented with the data you sending while the data moves from point A to point B in cloud.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cloud-computing"
    }
]